<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Bud Parr</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/article/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Bud Parr</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.budparr.com/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some Early Articles on Static Site Generators</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2014/08/02/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2014/08/02/getting-started/</guid><description>Here are some of the blog posts that first got me excited about the potential for static site generators:
&amp;ldquo;Meet the Obama campaign&amp;rsquo;s $250 million fundraising platform&amp;rdquo;, by Kyle Rush &amp;ldquo;How We Build CMS-Free Websites&amp;rdquo;, by Dave Cole at Development Seed Why? &amp;ldquo;The Great Web Slowdown [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;rdquo;, by Tammy Everts &amp;ldquo;Welcome to the Post-CMS World&amp;rdquo;, by Ben Balter Not the app! &amp;ldquo;Healthcare.gov: Code Developed by the People and for the People, Released Back to the People&amp;rdquo; by Alex Howard at The Atlantic</description></item><item><title>Speaking at the CUNY Publishing Institute</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2014/06/05/speaking-at-cuny-publishing-institute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2014/06/05/speaking-at-cuny-publishing-institute/</guid><description>For several years now, I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken annually at the CUNY Publishing Institute run by John Oakes of OR Books. Here&amp;rsquo;s a great article John wrote about the Institute for the Journal of Electronic Publishing: &amp;ldquo;By the Book: A New Approach to Teaching the Art of Book Publishing&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>László Krasznahorkai and Colm Tóibín</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2014/05/06/krasznahorkai-event/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2014/05/06/krasznahorkai-event/</guid><description>I wrote a brief piece on seeing Colm Tóibín interview László Krasznahorkai at a PEN World Voices Festival event. It was a truly fascinating conversation. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt:
I found one of the most interesting facts about Mr. Krasznahorkai is the way he combines his love of travel (or more likely, love of being in different places) with his love of music. He said that he plays several instruments and that while traveling he seeks out music, but will then, the very next day, try to find the instrument that he heard and play it himself.</description></item><item><title>The No-db Landscape (part 1)</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2014/03/14/static-site-generator-landscape/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2014/03/14/static-site-generator-landscape/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s no coincidence that as I&amp;rsquo;ve become obsessed with website performance I&amp;rsquo;ve also become enamored with building sites with no database. They&amp;rsquo;re unequivocally faster, simpler to maintain and build, and more secure and stable than database-driven websites. There are tradeoffs of course, but in my view well worth it. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand the talk I see about static sites being for &amp;ldquo;hackers&amp;rdquo; or small or simple sites. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some large, complex and highly trafficked sites built this way.</description></item><item><title>The Basics of Markdown Tutorial</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/article/2014-03-09-markdown-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/article/2014-03-09-markdown-tutorial/</guid><description>An abreviated form of this article is available as a Gist on Github
What is Markdown? Markdown is a formatting syntax that allows you to write in plain text in any editing program, but still format your document like you would with a word processor. It was created to convert plain text into HTML for publishing on the web and happens to be super easy to write and just as easy to read even without being converted.</description></item><item><title>Want to Speed up Your Website? Skip the database</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2014/03/06/static-site-generators-introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2014/03/06/static-site-generators-introduction/</guid><description>note: This post was written at the beginning of 2014; the tools mentioned in this post are now outdated, but the ideas behind the paradigm are growing ever more relevant today in 2020.
The Very Brief History In 2012 developers for the Obama re-election campaign moved from the ExpressionEngine-based website of the prior campaign to a practically retro HTML site with no content management system. Only this wasn&amp;rsquo;t 1999 and the website was actually quite modern, having been generated by the popular open source software called Jekyll1.</description></item><item><title>Murakami on the Train</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2014/01/15/murakami-on-the-train/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2014/01/15/murakami-on-the-train/</guid><description>On the train this morning I stood next to a man reading the same book I was reading and on the same page. The book was published over a decade ago and over 700 pages in total so I thought that was some coincidence. I read looking over at his book for a while. It was difficult because I had on my reading glasses, but I could tell it was the same page.</description></item><item><title>What an Author Site Should Look Like</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2013/09/30/what-an-author-site-should-look-like/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2013/09/30/what-an-author-site-should-look-like/</guid><description>I wrote a piece called What an Author Site Should Look Like and published it on the new publishing platform Medium. You can read it there, but here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt:
Nobody Cares About You
This goes for any website. Readers don’t spend a lot of time on any website and they click very little. Blogs and about pages are often draws, but that’s it. Any website should do as little as possible and be about the person visiting it, not an overdesigned marketing-copy-ladened beast.</description></item><item><title>Me, The Summer Vacation Reading Issue</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2013/08/15/the-summer-vacation-reading-issue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2013/08/15/the-summer-vacation-reading-issue/</guid><description>FINALLY. Vacation. Long overdue and a chance to catch up on some reading. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m taking to the beach:
The Guy Davenport Reader. I&amp;rsquo;ve read Geographies of the Imagination and A Table of Green Fields, which is incomprehensibly wonderful, so this looks like an irresistible collection.
Hypothermia, by Álvaro Enrigue. I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a long time for this collection, since reading Enrigue&amp;rsquo;s On the Death of the Author at Words Without Borders.</description></item><item><title>I Like Literature more than Books, so Damn Me</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2012/11/17/i-like-literature-more-than-books-so-damn-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2012/11/17/i-like-literature-more-than-books-so-damn-me/</guid><description>This is a cross-post of my comment on Andrew Piper&amp;rsquo;s article on Slate: &amp;ldquo;Out of Touch - E-reading isn’t reading.&amp;quot;Piper says:
Indeed, Tim Parks points out at the New York Review of Booksthat:
What the sentimentality of this article ignores is the reality books and reading face today. Ebooks represent an opportunity for access and choice. So many children around the world don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury you describe, and literacy is - amazingly - a major issue around the world.</description></item><item><title>My Life in CIA, by Harry Mathews</title><link>https://www.budparr.com/2005/12/15/my-life-in-cia-by-harry-mathews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.budparr.com/2005/12/15/my-life-in-cia-by-harry-mathews/</guid><description>Around his early 40s a man looks at his life, searches, and more often than not he finds his youth has gone missing. If he has the means he buys a sports car or a boat, or if he&amp;rsquo;s Harry Mathews he becomes a spy for CIA.
Well, not really a spy; he pretended. He pretended to be a spy because circumstances opened themselves to it and he was an adventurous, creative guy who also happened to be a little bored.</description></item></channel></rss>