<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/"/>
 <updated>2014-03-05T12:33:20-05:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The New York Times: Polk Award for Silver</title>
   <link href="/media/2012/04/05/polk-award/"/>
   <updated>2012-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2012/04/05/polk-award</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Three Bloomberg News reporters — Ben Elgin, Alan Katz and Vernon Silver — won the international reporting award for articles about Western companies that sell surveillance technology and equipment to repressive governments for use against opposition figures. Their stories showed how telephone transcripts generated by German computers had led to the arrest and torture of a human rights activist in Bahrain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/20/nyregion/anthony-shadid-times-correspondent-posthumously-honored.html&quot;&gt;Link: Polk Award for International Reporting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bob Hecht, Euphronios Dealer, Dies at 92</title>
   <link href="/news/2012/02/11/bob-hecht-euphronios-dealer-dies-at-92/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2012/02/11/bob-hecht-euphronios-dealer-dies-at-92</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Robert_Hecht.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hecht in Rome&quot;&gt;
Hecht in Rome&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Hecht, the American art dealer who brought the world the finest vases by the greatest Greek vase painter (and spawned the globetrotting tales of intrigue behind them) died in Paris this week. His death comes less than a month after his trial in Rome came to an end when the statute of limitations ran out on charges related to the Euphronios krater and other artifacts. His lifelong adventure ended with a clean criminal record and his most famous vases back on Italian soil. Until the finish, he had a twinkle in his eye, and I thank him for sharing what he could about his incredible life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/10/arts/design/robert-hecht-antiquities-dealer-dies-at-92.html&quot;&gt;NYT: Bob Hecht, 92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lost Chalice Found—and Fixed</title>
   <link href="/news/2010/12/31/lost-chalice/"/>
   <updated>2010-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2010/12/31/lost-chalice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/KylixVillaGiulia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Once shattered, on display for first time in 20 years&quot;&gt;
Once shattered, on display for first time in 20 years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The oldest known vase by the Leonardo da Vinci of ancient Greece has emerged from hiding after two decades. Last seen in public at a June 1990 auction at Sotheby’s in New York, Euphronios’ Sarpedon kylix has gone on display at Rome’s Villa Giulia museum with no fanfare or public announcement. Making the appearance more significant, the cup has been repaired—fixing the damage done when a Swiss police officer dropped it during an inventory of antiquities seized from dealer Giacomo Medici at the Geneva Freeport in 1995. The “lost chalice” now shares a glass case with a handful of other vases in a room dedicated to artifacts returned to Italy by American museums and collectors. Its label, which has no accession number, describes it as coming from the Geneva raid (and doesn’t mention that, technically, it’s still Medici’s property, pending the resolution of his legal cases).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cup is in good company: the case next to it holds another rare, signed Euphronios, a fragmentary krater depicting Athena that was sold at the same auction and later given to Italy by collector Shelby White. The repaired kylix has been on display since at least May (when I first spotted it there) and I’ve been waiting to see if there’d be any announcement before posting on it. As this is the biggest development in Greek pots for 2010, New Year’s Eve seemed like a good time. What remains to be seen is if it will ever get displayed alongside its bigger twin, the Met’s former “Euphronios Krater.” That vase, which depicts the same scene, is also at Villa Giulia, in a separate wing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>True Trial Ends</title>
   <link href="/news/2010/10/16/true-trial-ends/"/>
   <updated>2010-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2010/10/16/true-trial-ends</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Rome trial of former Getty antiquities chief Marion True fizzled out after five years when the statute of limitations ran out on the charges. True, who denied the allegations that she’d played a role in stocking the California museum with artifacts looted from Italy, never got to present her defense. It’s just a matter of months before the clock also runs out on charges against her co-defendant, Bob Hecht, who is accused of dealing in loot including the Euphronios krater, and also says he’s innocent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2010/10/14/arts/design/14true.html?ref=marion_true&quot;&gt;NYT: True’s Rome Trial Ends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>True: “greatest contempt” for Getty</title>
   <link href="/news/2010/10/16/true-greatest-conte/"/>
   <updated>2010-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2010/10/16/true-greatest-conte</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Former Getty curator Marion True finally gets her well-deserved say now that her Rome trial is over. In a stunning interview by Hugh Eakin (published on The New Yorker’s Web site) True tells off both the Italians (who had charged her in dealing with loot) and the Getty (which had been paying her legal bills). “My greatest sadness is that the Italians were able to intimidate the entire American art world, and especially museums, without having to produce any evidence at all,” she says. Of the Getty, which she essentially says hung her out to dry: “I have nothing but the greatest contempt for them in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2010/10/marion-true.html&quot;&gt;New Yorker: True Speaks Out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An Etruscan Lord Elgin</title>
   <link href="/news/2010/05/08/an-etruscan-lord-elgin/"/>
   <updated>2010-05-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
   <id>/news/2010/05/08/an-etruscan-lord-elgin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a compelling twist, Michael Kimmelman shows how Italy winning back the Krater makes a good argument for the British Museum keeping the Parthenon Marbles: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stolen property is stolen property. But how curious that an ancient Greek vase, which centuries after it was made came into the possession of an Etruscan collector (a kind of ancient Elgin) living on what is now the outskirts of Rome, and then ended up buried for thousands of years below what became modern Italy, is today Italian cultural patrimony. By that definition, Elgin’s loot is arguably British patrimony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/09/arts/09abroad.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;NYT: Culture’s Borders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Troy’s Gold and Bob Hecht</title>
   <link href="/news/2010/01/31/troys-gold-and-bob-hecht/"/>
   <updated>2010-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2010/01/31/troys-gold-and-bob-hecht</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Robert_Hecht.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hecht in Rome&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hecht in Rome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A feature in the Philadelphia Inquirer revives the mystery of the Penn Museum&amp;rsquo;s gold—whether it came from Troy, and how it got to America—and in the process reveals that the dealer behind the sale was the very same man who brought the Euphronios krater to the Metropolitan Museum of Art: Bob Hecht.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hecht confirmed that he was indeed the source of Penn’s Trojan-style gold, with Allen acting as his agent. Hecht easily recalled the pieces and proclaimed them ‘beautiful.’ He said he had purchased them from another dealer, George Zakos, who is dead… He said Zakos, who lived in Switzerland, had not shared the objects’ history. ‘He didn’t say, and I didn’t ask,’ Hecht said. ‘I thought it was beautiful, and I thought it was genuine.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philly.com/philly/news/homepage/20100131_Tracing_ancient_roots_of_Penn_Museum_s_gold.html?viewAll=y&quot;&gt;Tracing the Gold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Thomas Hoving, Met Chief and Journalist, Dies</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/12/10/thomas-hoving-dies-at-78/"/>
   <updated>2009-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/12/10/thomas-hoving-dies-at-78</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/popup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thomas Hoving (NYT)&quot;&gt;
Thomas Hoving (NYT)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Hoving, the former Met director who brought us King Tut and the Euphronios krater, has died. He was 78. Hoving loved an adventure. And he made the mummies dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/12/11/arts/design/11hoving.html&quot;&gt;NYT: Hoving, Who Shook Up the Met, Dies at 78&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Met’s von Bothmer Dies at 90</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/10/17/mets-von-bothmer-dies-at-90/"/>
   <updated>2009-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/10/17/mets-von-bothmer-dies-at-90</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/botmerspan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dietrich von Bothmer&quot;&gt;
Dietrich von Bothmer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An era in the study and collecting of Greek vases has come to an end with the death of Dietrich von Bothmer, whose modern career became intertwined with the ancient work of the artist Euphronios. From the first Euphronios he saw (in Berlin), which inspired his vocation, to the famous krater he helped the Metropolitan Museum of Art buy in 1972, to the one that got away—the krater’s smaller twin chalice, which he twice tried to acquire (in 1973 and 1990)—Dietrich von Bothmer’s biography became inseparable from that of the Athenian master and his pottery. While a chapter has come to a close, neither man’s story is over. The documents, photos and vase fragments he’s left behind in his files (NYT photo, above) and other archives may allow the curator and professor to keep illuminating the world of ancient art, even after his passing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/10/15/arts/15bothmer.html&quot;&gt;NYT: Dietrich von Bothmer, Curator and Art Historian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wall Street Journal: A Celebrity in Low-Key Digs</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/10/01/wall-street-journal-a-celebrity-in-low-key-digs/"/>
   <updated>2009-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/10/01/wall-street-journal-a-celebrity-in-low-key-digs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Silver, chronicler of the criminals, curators, detectives and politicians who have chased after the bowl in recent decades, insists that their story too is now an essential part of the krater’s significance, and thus an important element in the way the museum should present it. “Objects accrue meanings over time,” he says. “People may go to jail today because of this 2,500-year-old pot. Reputations have been won and lost because of it. To label it as just a work of art would be a mistake.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203863204574345011111945666.html&quot;&gt;WSJ on The Lost Chalice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Lost Chalice: SmartMoney’s 5 Smart Books</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/10/01/smart-moneys-5-smart-books/"/>
   <updated>2009-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/10/01/smart-moneys-5-smart-books</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lost Chalice&lt;/em&gt; is the fascinating story of how a band of grave robbers turned up two priceless ancient works of art — and how these ill-gotten masterpieces made their way to Sotheby’s, to private collections and to the Metropolitan Museum of Art. Silver shows how the illicit trade of stolen antiquities implicates the art world’s most prestigious institutions. He takes us alongside detectives and reporters who doggedly pursue elusive treasures across decades and continents, chasing leads to Switzerland, Beirut…and Malibu. Millions are made while laws — and irreplaceable artworks — are broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smartmoney.com/Spending/Deals/5-Smart-Books-Our-Staffs-Latest-Picks/&quot;&gt;SmartMoney on The Lost Chalice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Met Curator Fills Gaps on Museum “Rogues”</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/10/01/mets-o/"/>
   <updated>2009-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/10/01/mets-o</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MuscarellaPhoto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oscar White Muscarella&quot;&gt;
Oscar White Muscarella&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curator Oscar White Muscarella, the longtime in-house critic of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, reviews a new book on the Met as a starting point to dredge up a few decades of alleged misdeeds and “clandestine acts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/HL0909/S00139.htm&quot;&gt;Muscarella: The Met/Rogues’ Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>NPR: Italy Cracks Down on Raiders of Lost Art</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/08/16/npr-italy-cracks-down-on-raiders-of-lost-art/"/>
   <updated>2009-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/08/16/npr-italy-cracks-down-on-raiders-of-lost-art</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;NPR’s Sylvia Poggioli reports: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The expert who helped nail down the exact spot where the pot was found is Vernon Silver, an American journalist with a degree in archaeology from Oxford. His new book, The Lost Chalice, traces the story of the looted vase’s travels from a tomb in Italy to Switzerland to New York and back to Italy through the labyrinthine world of smugglers and shady dealers in an illicit trade that fed a network of American collectors and institutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.npr.org/v2/?i=111734951&amp;#38;m=111748597&amp;#38;t=audio&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; wmode=&quot;opaque&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; base=&quot;http://www.npr.org&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=111734951&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;NPR: Italy Cracks Down on Raiders of Lost Art&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Providence Journal: “Vernon Silver’s fascinating account”</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/07/18/providence-journal-vernon-silvers-fascinating-account/"/>
   <updated>2009-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/07/18/providence-journal-vernon-silvers-fascinating-account</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;a world of incredible secrecy, where art rises into view only to disappear for decades, where sales are anonymous, museum officials turn blind eyes, and where beauty is measured in dollars and euros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projo.com/books/content/BOOK-LOST-CHALICE_07-12-09_NUEQOTP_v12.f78b7b.html&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;ProJo: The Lost Chalice&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Medici Off The Hook For Krater?</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/07/18/medici-off-the-hook-for-krater/"/>
   <updated>2009-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/07/18/medici-off-the-hook-for-krater</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While the Rome appeals court affirmed Giacomo Medici’s conviction for antiquities trafficking, it absolved him on charges of handling objects that ended up at the Met—on what appears to be a procedural technicality. Only the full, written sentence, expected within three months, will explain what this means for the Euphronios krater.
Bloomberg: Rome Court Upholds Medici Conviction&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The New York Times on “The Lost Chalice”</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/07/07/the-new-york-times-on-the-lost-chalice/"/>
   <updated>2009-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/07/07/the-new-york-times-on-the-lost-chalice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/abroad2_650.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vernon at the tomb&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Vernon at the tomb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New York Times’ Michael Kimmelman has published a terrific feature on “The Lost Chalice” and the road trip we took the other day to the overgrown Etruscan countryside. First we tromped around the long-sought site of the clandestine dig that four decades ago uncovered some of the world’s finest ancient art. Then I introduced him to a key character from “The Lost Chalice,” the last known surviving member of the tomb-robbing team that unearthed the haul. And on the way back into Rome we stopped to see the biggest prize from the illicit excavation—the Euphronios krater— itself in a new context at the Villa Giulia museum, far from its former home in New York’s Met.
Stolen Beauty: A Greek Urn’s Underworld&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The New York Times: A Greek Urn’s Underworld</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/07/07/the-new-york-times-a-greek-urns-underworld/"/>
   <updated>2009-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/07/07/the-new-york-times-a-greek-urns-underworld</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“The Lost Chalice: The Epic Hunt for a Priceless Masterpiece,” just published by William Morrow, makes a first-class page turner out of the stolen krater’s travels from ancient Greece to Etruscan Italy to New York and then back here — and of the travails of another work also by the sublime Euphronios, a kylix, or chalice, which was looted from the same spot here in Cerveteri, a town northwest of Rome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vernon Silver, a 40-year-old American journalist and a doctoral student in archaeology at Oxford, wrote the book. “This is the whole illicit antiquities trade writ small,” he said a few days ago. “The two works started out in the hands of the same Greek artist, 2,500 years ago, ended up going through the same shady Italian dealer by different routes to America, one the public route, the other underground, and both end up back here in Italy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tale is one neither Met officials nor Italian authorities will be pleased to find so conscientiously recounted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/07/08/arts/design/08abroad.html?ref=design&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stolen Beauty: A Greek Urn’s Underworld&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>“The Lost Chalice” on MarketWatch with Jon Friedman</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/07/06/the-lost-chalice-on-marketwatch-with-jon-friedman/"/>
   <updated>2009-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/07/06/the-lost-chalice-on-marketwatch-with-jon-friedman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;288&quot; src=&quot;http://live.wsj.com/public/page/embed-646C1CD8_73A7_45E6_9A52_FCF993DE9C2B.html&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Exhibitionists: “Rogues’ Gallery” Reviewed</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/06/27/exhibitionists-rogues-gallery-reviewed/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/06/27/exhibitionists-rogues-gallery-reviewed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Michael Gross’ new book on the Met, “Rogues’ Gallery,” touches on the Euphronios episode and some of the characters behind it. It’s reviewed in The New York Times this Sunday.
Exhibitionists&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How eBay Fakes May Be Saving Tombs</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/06/24/how-ebay-fakes-may-be-saving-tombs/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/06/24/how-ebay-fakes-may-be-saving-tombs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The New York Times takes a look at the role fakes (and their sale online) may have in reducing illicit excavation of genuine antiquities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ideas.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/06/24/how-fakes-on-ebay-save-antiquities/&quot;&gt;Idea of the Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hoving Takes On The Getty</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/06/17/hoving-takes-on-the-getty/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/06/17/hoving-takes-on-the-getty</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thomas Hoving, the former Met director, has been publishing his memoirs online. A recent chapter takes on fakes, fraud and repatriation from some big museums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artnet.com/magazineus/features/hoving/artful-tom-chapter-thirty-one6-12-09.asp&quot;&gt;Artful Tom: The Getty Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Euphronios Krater’s New Home</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/06/09/t/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/06/09/t</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/KraterVillaGiulia.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sarpedon in Rome&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sarpedon in Rome&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sarpedon krater by Euphronios went on display a few weeks ago at its new permanent (until further notice) home at Rome’s Villa Giulia museum. The Metropolitan Museum of Art returned the krater to Italy in January 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind the krater is the huge kylix potted by Euphronios and painted by Onesimos—the one the J. Paul Getty Museum surrendered to Italy in 1999, prompting Roman art dealer Giacomo Medici to hand over three fragments from the cup. The fragments, which haven’t been glued into the previously restored kylix, are also in the display case.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Krater Pulled From Auction in New York</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/06/04/krater-pulled-from-auction-in-new-york/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/06/04/krater-pulled-from-auction-in-new-york</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;U.S. Customs says a krater got yanked from auction in New York, in part because of its possible link to a certain Roman art dealer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The investigation into the Corinthian column krater revealed it may have been illegally introduced into the art market by Giacomo Medici and a third party at Sotheby’s Auction house in 1985.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ice.gov/pi/nr/0906/090601newyork.htm&quot;&gt;ICE Press Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Thomas Hoving, former director of the Metropolitan Museum of Art</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/06/01/thomas-hoving-former-director-of-the-metropolitan-museum-of-art/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/06/01/thomas-hoving-former-director-of-the-metropolitan-museum-of-art</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In his brilliant The Lost Chalice Vernon Silver has gone far beyond merely slicing open the Gordion knot obscuring the world-famous ancient Greek chalices made by Euphronios, the Leonardo of the 6th century BC, he has patiently untied that knot in a spine-tingling read.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Daily Beast: “The Tomb Robbers”</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/06/01/the-tomb-robbers/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/06/01/the-tomb-robbers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the trail of a looted chalice, Vernon Silver exposes the dark side of the antiquities trade, from tomb robbers in Italy to museum curators in New York and Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has ever stood under the halogen lights of a museum and wondered just where, exactly, an Etruscan artifact is from, Vernon Silver has the answer, which may involve tomb raiders, smugglers, unscrupulous art dealers, and willfully blind museum curators. A Rome-based correspondent for Bloomberg who is also an Oxford-trained archeologist, Silver, in his new book, The Lost Chalice, describes the seedy underworld of the antiquities trade in such vivid detail that one can almost smell the fresh earth of a pillaged archeological site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unbridled looting of Italy’s buried treasures before 1970 is one of this country’s darkest cultural chapters. Thousands of valuable artifacts were fished from the soil and sold to art dealers, who passed them on to private collectors and major museums. A 1970 Unesco convention on cultural heritage exposed the illicit practice and established procedures for repatriating stolen goods. Countries trying to reclaim their antiquities from museums around the world have better luck with those acquired after the 1970 accord. Those acquired before the pact generally stay on the museum shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thedailybeast.com/blogs-and-stories/2009-05-30/the-tomb-robbers/full/&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Tomb Robbers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Lost Chalice Released Today</title>
   <link href="/news/2009/06/01/the-lost-chalice-released-today/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/news/2009/06/01/the-lost-chalice-released-today</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lost Chalice&lt;/em&gt; is out. Enjoy, and thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sharon Waxman, author of Loot</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/06/01/sharon-waxman-author-of-loot/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/06/01/sharon-waxman-author-of-loot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Setting up his tale as a mystery to be solved Silver takes a micro approach to a great big problem, that of looted antiquities in modern times&amp;hellip; a welcome glimpse into the modern, secret journey of such ancient objects.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sharonwaxman.typepad.com/loot/2009/04/vernon-silver-takes-on-giacomo-medici-.html&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sharon Waxman, author of Loot on The Lost Chalice&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kirkus Reviews</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/06/01/kirkus-reviews/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/06/01/kirkus-reviews</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Vernon&amp;rsquo;s sharply rendered account is engrossing. A densely packed, dizzyingly detailed tale of art and espionage.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>James L. Swanson, author of Manhunt</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/06/01/james-l-swanson-author-of-manhunt/"/>
   <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/06/01/james-l-swanson-author-of-manhunt</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vernon Silver has written an utterly compelling, page-turner of a book. The Lost Chalice is a riveting story of tomb robbers and antiquities smugglers, high-stakes auctioneers and the princely chiefs of the world’s most prestigious museums—all vying to get their hands on an ancient masterpiece. It’s a terrific read, from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Publishers Weekly</title>
   <link href="/media/2009/05/31/publishers-weekly/"/>
   <updated>2009-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>/media/2009/05/31/publishers-weekly</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“A captivating tale of ancient art as a modern hot commodity&amp;hellip; Silver’s telling is infused with an infectious curiosity about the illicit art trade and an equally infectious appreciation of the art itself. ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publishersweekly.com/article/CA6660208.html?industryid=47263&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Publishers Weekly&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
